<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<!--
  (C) Copyright 2006-2014 Hewlett-Packard Development Company, L.P.
-->

<!--
    Onboard Administrator Wizard strings file
    
    The string content in this file is used by the Onboard Administrator
    GUI for localization purposes.  This file can be renamed and then 
    translated into other languages.  Refer to the localization specification
    for more information.
    
-->

<strings xml:lang="en">
  <!-- Wizard general terms -->
  <value key="step">Step</value>
  <value key="of">of</value>
  <value key="skip">Skip</value>
  <value key="next">Next</value>
  <value key="previous">Previous</value>
  <value key="leftArrow">&lt;</value>
  <value key="rightArrow">&gt;</value>
  <value key="cancel">Cancel</value>
  <value key="finish">Finish</value>
  <value key="ALL">ALL</value>
  <value key="clickHere">Click here </value>
  
  <!-- Wizard Step titles -->
  <value key="firstTimeSetupWizard">First Time Setup Wizard</value>
  <value key="firmwareUpdateWizard">Firmware Update Wizard</value>
  <value key="setupInitialSettings">Set up initial enclosure and server settings</value>
  <value key="updateMultipleEnclosures">Update Firmware of Multiple Linked Enclosures</value>
  <value key="welcome">Welcome</value>
  <value key="enclosureSelection">Enclosure Selection</value>
  <value key="selectEnclosures">Select Enclosures</value>
  <value key="chooseFirmwareSource">Choose Firmware Source</value>
  <value key="installFirmware">Install Firmware</value>
  <value key="configManagement">Configuration Management</value>
  <value key="rackAndEnclosureSettings">Rack and Enclosure Settings</value>
  <value key="adminAccountSetup">Administrator Account Setup</value>
  <value key="localUserAccounts">Local User Accounts</value>
  <value key="userSettings">User Settings</value>
  <value key="ebipa">Enclosure Bay IP Addressing</value>
  <value key="ebipaSettings">IPv4</value>
  <value key="ebipav6Settings">IPv6</value>
  <value key="directoryGroups">Directory Groups</value>
  <value key="groupSettings">Group Settings</value>
  <value key="directorySettings">Directory Settings</value>
  <value key="oaNetworkSettings">Onboard Administrator Network Settings</value>
  <value key="snmpSettings">Enclosure SNMP Settings</value>
  <value key="powerManagement">Power Management</value>
  <value key="finish">Finish</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Welcome -->
  <value key="welcomePara1">This wizard will assist you in setting up your enclosures. It is run automatically the first time the Onboard Administrator is started.</value>
  <value key="welcomePara2a">Steps may be skipped when accompanied by a </value>
  <value key="welcomePara2b"> button. The settings for each step will be applied when the </value>
  <value key="welcomePara2c"> button is clicked.</value>  
  
  <!-- Step Text: Enclosure Selection -->
  <value key="encSelectPara1">The following list of enclosures has been detected. Up to seven enclosures may be connected via the enclosure link ports located on the back of each enclosure.</value>
  <value key="encSelectPara2a">You are initially signed in to the enclosure designated as "Primary Connection."  To set up more than one enclosure at	this time, select multiple enclosures below using the checkboxes provided. The settings from each wizard step will be applied to </value>
  <value key="encSelectPara2b"> selected enclosures when the </value>
  <value key="encSelectPara2c"> button is clicked.  To set up one enclosure at a time, select only one enclosure below.</value>
  <value key="encSelectPara3">For enclosures listed as "Linked - Not Signed In" the Administrator's password must be entered in the textboxes	provided. Settings can not be applied to enclosures listed as "Linked - Not Signed In."</value>
  <value key="encSelectPara4">Each Onboard Administrator module has a factory-set Administrator account password.  For security, please remove this tag once you have set a unique Administrator account password. The Administrator account password can	be retrieved by connecting to the Onboard Administrator's serial port.  Please see the Onboard Administrator User Guide for instructions.</value>
  <value key="encSelectPara5">The firmware version on linked enclosures must match the firmware version on the primary enclosure, and the user account must be an Administrator with Onboard Administrator access to participate in this wizard.</value>
  <value key="insufficientPrivs">* Insufficient privileges for the currently signed in user account.</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Configuration Management -->
  <value key="configManagePara1">Skip this step if you do not have any previously saved configuration files. If you have a configuration script created from a previous setup you may use it to setup the enclosures you selected.</value>
  <value key="configManagePara2">If the script is located on a web server you may provide the URL to the script. If you have a script file on a local drive you may upload it.</value>
  <value key="configManagePara3">Do not directly apply a configuration script from another enclosure without removing or changing possibly unique settings such as the enclosure Asset Tag,	enclosure name, static IP addresses and EBIPA settings.</value>
  <value key="configManagePara4">Select the enclosure to which you want to apply this script:</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Rack and Enclosure Settings -->
  <value key="rackSettingsPara1">You may use the following form to provide a common name and common time settings for your rack. You may also provide unique names and asset tags for each of the enclosures you selected.</value>
  <value key="rackSettingsPara2">Please note: the date and time settings cannot be applied here if NTP is enabled. Any enclosures that have NTP enabled require that their date and time settings be configured independently of the wizard.</value>
  <value key="rackSettingsPara3">These date and time settings will be applied to all of the selected enclosures on the link.</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Administrator Account Setup -->
  <value key="adminAccountPara1">The Administrator account is the master administrator account for the enclosure. This account has all possible privileges for all devices in the enclosure. These account settings will be applied to the built-in Administrator account for each enclosure you have selected.</value>
  <value key="adminAccountPara2">Note: If this is your first time logging in, there is a physical tag attached to the Onboard Administrator module which contains the factory-set password.</value>
  <value key="adminAccountPara3">Enabling PIN protection will require a PIN code to be entered before using the enclosure's Insight Display. The PIN is alpha-numeric and must have a length from one to six characters.</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Local User Accounts -->
  <value key="localAccountsPara1">The Onboard Administrator supports up to 30 local user accounts when FIPS is not enabled, and 21 local user accounts when FIPS is enabled. Users can be granted or denied access to specific device bays in the enclosure.</value>
  <value key="localAccountsPara2a">The list below displays the currently configured users in the enclosure you are signed in to. You may add, edit, and delete users from this screen.</value>
  <value key="localAccountsPara2b">to continue when you are finished configuring users.</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: User Settings -->
  <value key="userSettingsPara1">Use this form to set up your new user's information and permissions. When you are finished, click </value>
  <value key="userSettingsPara2">Use this form to modify a current user's information and permissions. When you are finished, click </value>
  <value key="userSettingsFormPara1">Multiple enclosure types have been selected for setup with this wizard.  Individual bay permissions may not be assigned here.</value>


  <!-- Step Text: Enclosure Bay IP Addressing -->
  <value key="ebipaPara1">Enclosure Bay IP Addressing (EBIPA) allows you to assign a range of fixed IP addresses to the device bays and/or interconnect bays in the enclosure.  These IP addresses will be used by the server blade iLO ports once inserted into a bay. In addition, an interconnect module (switch) management port will use the pre-assigned IP address once inserted into the interconnect bay.</value>
  <value key="ebipaPara2">Note: Skip this step if your network has an external DHCP service, or if you wish to manually assign static IP addresses one by one to the server blades and interconnect modules.</value>
  <value key="ebipaPara3">For more information on EBIPA, click on the Help icon "?" at the top right of this screen.</value>
  <value key="ebipaPara4a">If you wish to include all of your enclosures in one range, choose the </value>
  <value key="ebipaPara4b"> option below. Otherwise, choose the </value>
  <value key="ebipaPara4c"> option to specify a unique address range for each enclosure.</value>
  <value key="ebipaPara5a"> to continue or </value>
  <value key="ebipaPara5b"> if you do not wish to use Enclosure Bay IP Addressing.</value>
  
 
  <!-- Step Text: EBIPA Settings -->
  <value key="ebipaSettingsPara1"></value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Directory Groups -->
  <value key="ldapGroupsPara1">Access to the enclosure can be controlled using an LDAP server. Directory accounts must be created before LDAP can be utilized.</value>
  <value key="ldapGroupsPara2">The list below displays the current directory groups that have been added to the Primary Connection's enclosure. You may add groups to all enclosures. You may only edit and delete groups from the Primary Connection's enclosure.</value>
  <value key="ldapGroupsPara3">If local users will be disabled in the next step you must add at least one valid directory group before enabling LDAP or you will be unable to sign in to the Onboard Administrator.</value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Group Settings -->
  <value key="ldapGroupSettingsPara1">Use this form to set up your new group's information and permissions.</value>
  <value key="ldapGroupSettingsPara2a">When you are finished, click </value>
  <value key="ldapGroupSettingsPara2b">.</value> <!-- for translated words -->
  <value key="ldapGroupSettingsPara3">Use this form to modify a current groups's information and permissions.</value>


  <!-- Step Text: Directory Settings -->
  <value key="ldapSettingsPara1">Access to enclosures can be controlled by LDAP groups in addition to local accounts.</value>
  <value key="ldapSettingsPara2a">If you would like to enable LDAP authentication, check the </value>
  <value key="ldapSettingsPara2b">Enable LDAP Authentication</value>
  <value key="ldapSettingsPara2c"> checkbox.</value>

  <!-- Step Text: Onboard Administrator Network Settings -->
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara1">The following network settings apply to the Onboard Administrators in each of the enclosures you selected.</value>
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara2">Use either a DHCP service to assign IP settings to your Onboard Administrators, or manually assign static IP settings. The Onboard Administrator's DNS name can be assigned under either setting.</value>
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara3"> Changing the network settings on the Onboard Administrator that you have signed in to will disconnect you from that Onboard Administrator. Once the settings are applied you will have to sign in to the Onboard Administrator again using the new settings.</value>
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara4">Changing the Onboard Administrator's DNS Name could cause a hostname mismatch on the SSL certificate. You may have to update the certificate information on any Onboard Administrator whose DNS Name is changed.</value>
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara5">Active Onboard Administrator Network Settings</value>
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara6">Standby Onboard Administrator Network Settings</value>
  <value key="oaNetSettingsPara7">Click Next to continue or Skip if you do not wish to change Onboard Administrator Network Settings.</value>
  <value key="activeIPSettingDHCP">Use DHCP for all Active Onboard Administrators</value>
  <value key="lblDDNS">Enable Dynamic DNS</value>
  <value key="activeIPSettingStatic">Use static IP settings for each Active Onboard Administrator</value>
  <value key="standbyIPSettingDHCP">Use DHCP for all Standby Onboard Administrators</value>
  <value key="standbyIPSettingStatic">Use static IP settings for each Standby Onboard Administrator</value>

  <!-- Step Text: Enclosure SNMP Settings -->
  <value key="snmpSettingsPara1">This function forwards alerts from the enclosure (power supplies, fans, the Onboard Administrator, enclosure thermals, etc.) to the specified alert destinations.</value>
  <value key="snmpSettingsPara2">Note: Individual server blades must be configured separately using iLO and Server Agents. Alert destinations will be added to and removed from all selected linked enclosures.</value>
  <value key="snmpUserSettingsPara1">Use this form to set up your new SNMP user's information. When you are finished, click Add User</value>
  <value key="snmpAlertSettingsPara1">Use this form to set up your new SNMP alert's information. When you are finished, click Add Alert</value>

  <!-- Step Text: Power Management -->
  <value key="powerManagePara1"></value>
  
  <!-- Step Text: Finish -->
  <value key="finishPara1a">Congratulations! You have successfully set up your enclosures. Click </value>
  <value key="finishPara1b">to exit the wizard.</value>
  <value key="finishPara2">to download a setup script for the process you just completed.</value>
  <value key="finishPara3">Do not automatically show this wizard again.</value>

  <!-- dialog and message text -->
  <value key="reallyCancelWizard">Are you sure you want to cancel this wizard?</value>
  <value key="doNotShowWizard">Do not automatically show this wizard again.</value>
  <value key="reallySkip">Are you sure you want to skip?</value>
  <value key="canStartWizardAgain">You can start this wizard again from the Wizards menu.</value>
  <value key="invalidStep">An invalid step was encountered.</value>
  <value key="returnToNextStep">Are you sure you want to exit and return to the next step in the wizard?</value>
  
  <!-- error text -->
  <value key="wizardLoadError">Wizard Load Error</value>

	<value key="wizScheduleDesc">To schedule a one-time firmware update, enter a valid date and time below. Both date and time must be specified.
	 To select individual devices that will updated, please use the Firmware Mangement configuration page in the main part of the GUI.</value>
  
</strings>
