<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DEditLocalUserCertificateInformationtab" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Edit Local User Certificate Information tab</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DEditLocalUserCertificateInformationtab.xml</source>
  <keywords>Two-Factor Authentication user certificates</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">When Two-Factor Authentication is enabled, you must have a user certificate to sign in to the Onboard Administrator. Users with administrator privileges can upload or map a valid certificate to a selected user.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  When the Onboard Administrator is operating in FIPS Mode, certificates must have a minimum RSA key length of 2048 bits, and the signature hash algorithm must be SHA1, SHA-224, SHA-256, SHA-384, or SHA-512. 
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">There are two methods for uploading certificates for use in HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator:</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">Paste certificate contents into the text field and click <b>Upload.</b></li>
          <li class="listbullet">Paste the URL of the certificate into the URL field and click <b>Apply.</b></li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">When the certificate is successfully uploaded, the SHA1 fingerprint of the user certificate appears.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">If you already have a certificate mapped to an account, the SHA1 fingerprint of the certificate appears. Any user with administrator privileges can delete their certificate and upload a new user certificate. When your certificate expires and is renewed, as long as the renewed certificate has the same subject name as the expired one, you do not need to upload the renewed certificate to the Onboard Administrator.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>