<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DEnclosureselection" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Enclosure Selection</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DEnclosureselection.xml</source>
  <keywords>enclosure selection selecting enclosures</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">The Enclosure Selection screen displays all discovered enclosures and selects the active enclosure, the enclosure you are signed in to, by default. The check box beside each enclosure enables you to select or deselect that enclosure. Selecting the check box beside <b>All Enclosures,</b> will toggle the check box for all the enclosures.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">Click <b>Refresh Topology</b> to update the rack topology information. When you select Refresh Topology, the Enclosure selection screen switches to the Linked Mode and all linked enclosures are displayed.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">Linked enclosures will have one of the following states:</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">Linked—Not Signed In. Select the enclosure and enter the Administrator password in the password text box. Authentication will be attempted when the Next button is clicked.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">Linked—Not Signed In with a card reader icon. This state indicates the linked enclosure is Two-Factor Authentication enabled but is not authenticated. This state occurs under two conditions:<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">The configuration is not supported. The primary enclosure must be enabled for Two-Factor Authentication and both the primary and linked enclosure must have the same credentials in order for the linked enclosure to authenticate using Two-Factor Authentication. If the primary enclosure does not have Two-Factor Authentication enabled, the linked enclosure with Two-Factor Authentication enabled is not selectable.</li><li class="listbullet2">If you click the Sign Out link on a Two-Factor Authenticated enabled enclosure that is already authenticated, this state is displayed. If you select this enclosure, authentication is attempted when the Next button is clicked.</li></ul></li>
          <li class="listbullet">Linked—Signed In with or without a card reader icon. This state indicates the linked enclosure is authenticated. If the enclosure information has not been loaded already, it will be loaded when the Next button is clicked.</li>
        </ul>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>