<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DEnclosurePowerSummary" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Enclosure Power Summary</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DEnclosurePowerSummary.xml</source>
  <keywords>device bay power summary Enclosure Dynamic Power Capping enclosure power summary fan power summary power summaries</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Enclosure Input Power Summary</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">Present Power is the input watts to the enclosure and is measured in Watts AC for power supplies with AC inputs and is measured in Watts DC for power supplies with DC inputs. Max Input Power is the highest expected input watts. If the Power Limit is set, then the Max Input Power is equal to the Power Limit. If the Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap is set and Enclosure Dynamic Power Capping is enabled, then the Max Input Power is equal to the Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap. If neither Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap nor Power Limit is set, then the Max Input Power of the enclosure is the expected input power for the enclosure to operate at maximum DC output capacity.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Enclosure Output Power Summary</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">When Enclosure Dynamic Power Capping is disabled, Power Capacity is based on the number of installed and operational power supplies, their DC output capacities, and the redundant Power Mode setting. Power Allocated is the total enclosure power output allocated for Device Bays, Interconnect Bays, and Fans. Power Available is Power Capacity minus Power Allocated.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">When Enclosure Dynamic Power Capping is enabled, Power Capacity is the Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap in Watts DC. Power Allocated is the minimum power the enclosure can be capped to in Watts DC. Power Available is Power Capacity minus Power Allocated. The total power allocated for Device Bays, Interconnect Bays, and Fans might not be equal to the Power Allocated for the enclosure, because the power cap on each server is controlled dynamically.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Enclosure Bay Output Power Allocation</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">Power Allocated in the enclosure is the total of the power allocations for all Device Bays, Interconnect Bays, and Fans.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Device Bay Power Summary</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">Each populated device bay is listed with the power allocated. If Enclosure Dynamic Power Capping is enabled, additional columns indicate compatible ProLiant server Power Cap, % Power Cap, and Present Power. The % Power Cap is computed based on current Power Cap Watts divided by the Power Allocated Watts. If Enclosure Dynamic Power Capping is enabled, a server blade requesting power is only permitted to turn on if the Power Available supports the request or the Onboard Administrator can change the power cap for other servers to support the request.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Interconnect Bay Power Summary</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">Each populated interconnect bay is listed with the power allocated.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Fan Power Summary</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">Fan power is allocated based on a fan-rule. Fan-rule is determined according to the enclosure type (c3000 or c7000) and occupied device bays. Both the power allocation for the fans and the total Present Power consumption of all the fans are listed.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To update power summary information, click <b>Refresh.</b></p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>