<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DFinish" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Finish</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DFinish.xml</source>
  <keywords>network settings</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="procedurelead-in">To view a current configuration for the enclosure:</p>
        <ol class="listnumber">
          <li class="listnumber">Click the <b>SHOW CONFIG</b> link. The configuration opens in a new browser window.</li>
          <li class="listnumber">To save the configuration as a text file, choose one of the following options:<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">If you use Microsoft Internet Explorer, select <b>Save As</b>.</li><li class="listbullet2">If you use Mozilla Firefox, select <b>Save Page As</b>.</li><li class="listbullet2">If you use Google Chrome, select <b>Save Link As</b>.</li></ul></li>
        </ol>
        <p class="bodytext">For security, the retrieved current configuration does not contain any user passwords. You can manually edit the script to add the user passwords after the user name on the ADD USER lines. Also, the retrieved current configuration does not contain any of the LCD settings (Lock Buttons, Enable PIN Protection, and PIN Code). These settings cannot be added from the configuration script.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To force the First Time Setup Wizard to run again the next time a user signs into the Onboard Administrator, clear the <b>Do not automatically start this wizard again</b> check box.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To save and exit the First Time Setup Wizard, click <b>Finish</b>. The First Time Setup Wizard screen closes and you are returned to the default main screen of HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>