<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DFirmwareupdate" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Firmware update</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DFirmwareupdate.xml</source>
  <keywords>firmware update firmware update source firmware downgrade USB key support</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">The current firmware version installed on the Onboard Administrator, both Active and Standby, appears on this screen. The current Onboard Administrator hardware version also appears on this screen.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Synchronize firmware</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">To synchronize the firmware on the Active and Standby Onboard Administrator to the same version of firmware, click <b>Synchronize Firmware</b>. A firmware image is created from the flash contents of the Onboard Administrator with the latest firmware version and is flashed to the Onboard Administrator with the oldest firmware version. The Onboard Administrator being upgraded reboots after the firmware is flashed.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To use the Synchronize Firmware feature:</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">Both Onboard Administrators must be running firmware version 2.10 or later.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">If VLAN is enabled on the Active Onboard Administrator, the Standby Onboard Administrator must have firmware compatible with the VLAN feature. If the Standby Onboard Administrator has an older firmware version that does not support VLAN, you must remove the Standby Onboard Administrator and update the firmware to a compatible version from a different enclosure.</li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Downgrade firmware</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Force Downgrade</b>—Use this option to force a downgrade of the Onboard Administrator to an earlier version. Selecting this option forces a downgrade of the firmware; current settings that are inapplicable to the earlier version may be lost. When the Onboard Administrator is in VC mode and IPv6 is enabled, the Virtual Connect Manager may specify a minimum expected firmware version for the Onboard Administrator. When this situation occurs, disabling Onboard Administrator IPv6 communication prior to the downgrade attempt makes it possible for VC to interoperate with older Onboard Administrator versions.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  This feature is disabled while in the FIPS Mode ON/DEBUG.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Update firmware</b>
        </p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/35928.png" alt="" />
              </p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">CAUTION: </b> In FIPS Mode ON/DEBUG, an upgrade to the current version of the Onboard Administrator from a version earlier than 4.40 retains the first 21 local user accounts that were created, including any reserved accounts such as the Administrator or Virtual Connect users. The remainder of the users are deleted.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Local File</b>—To update firmware on the Active Onboard Administrator from a local file, browse to the firmware image file or enter the path of the firmware image file in the text box. The maximum number of characters in the file path is 256. Click <b>Upload</b>.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Image URL</b>—To update firmware on the Active Onboard Administrator from a file located on a web server:</p>
        <ol class="listnumber2">
          <li class="listnumber2">Enter an http:// path to the firmware image file. Supported protocols are HTTP, FTP, and TFTP. The URL is formatted as: protocol://host/path/filename. The URL syntax for IPv6 addresses is:<p class="listcontinue2">protocol://[&lt;ipv6 address&gt;]/path/file</p><p class="listcontinue2">The maximum length of the URL is 511 characters. 
      If your FTP server does not support anonymous logins, then you can specify a user name and password within the URL formatted as: ftp://username:password@host/path/filename</p><p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  When using the FTP protocol, specify the image’s URL path in this format, specifying a double slash (//) prior to the host/path/filename portion of the URL: ftp://user:password@//host/path/filename.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /><p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  Because of a change in behavior beginning with Onboard Administrator v4.11, if you specify a single slash (/) instead of double slashes, some FTP servers will search for the image file using your home directory as the relative root path (/home/user/path/filename). Specifying the recommended double slashes ensures that the FTP server will use the absolute path (/path/filename) to search for the image.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /></li>
          <li class="listnumber2">Enter the URL, and then click <b>Apply</b>.</li>
          <li class="listnumber2">After clicking <b>Upload </b>or <b>Apply</b>, a window displays the progress of the firmware download. When the download completes, you are signed off the Onboard Administrator; you must sign in again.</li>
        </ol>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>USB File</b>—To update firmware on the Active Onboard Administrator from an image located on a USB key, select a file from the menu, and then click <b>Apply</b>.<b></b>This field appears only when a USB key is detected in the Active Onboard Administrator USB port and firmware images are present on the USB key. </p>
        <p class="bodytext">If you initiated the firmware update, a timer appears and other users receive a dialog box informing them that the enclosure is powering down and rebooting. After the enclosure reboots, you must sign in again.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">If two enclosures are attached, the firmware update process flashes the Standby Onboard Administrator first and then flashes the primary Onboard Administrator. If you are unable to connect immediately following a firmware update, wait 30 seconds for the enclosure to become available on the network.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Enclosure Firmware Management</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">Update the Onboard Administrator from an image on a firmware ISO. Enclosure Firmware Management must be enabled, and a valid URL must be specified in the Enclosure Firmware Management settings. For more information, see "<a href="DEnclosureFirmwareManagement.xml">Enclosure Firmware Management</a>."</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To update the Onboard Administrator, click <b>Apply</b>.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Installing a previous version</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">To install a previous version of the firmware, select the <b>Force downgrade</b> box from the Firmware Information section of the screen. Select the firmware file by browsing locally or by locating a URL using the input boxes. If you downgrade Onboard Administrator firmware to 2.31 or lower, you will lose any Directory groups beyond the first five groups. Onboard Administrator versions higher than 2.31 support 30 groups, while earlier versions only support five groups. After the first five groups, you will lock out additional directory users.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To downgrade to a previous version with IPv6 enabled, VC requires an Onboard Administrator minimum firmware version. To proceed with the downgrade, disable IPv6 and try again. </p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>