<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DFTSWOAnetworkIPV4settings" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Network IPv4 Settings</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DFTSWOAnetworkIPV4settings.xml</source>
  <keywords>dynamic DNS network settings</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>First Time Setup Wizard Network IPv4 Settings</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">The Onboard Administrator allows the IPv4 network configuration to be based either on dynamically assigned IP addresses obtained from a DHCP server or on static IP addresses that you specify manually. You choose the basis for network configuration by selecting the appropriate radio button. If you choose DHCP, you can enable Dynamic DNS.</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Use DHCP for all Active (or Standby) <b>Onboard Administrator</b></b>—Obtains the IP address for the Onboard Administrator from a DHCP server. The Standby check box is only shown if there is a Standby Onboard Administrator in the enclosure.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Enable Dynamic DNS</b>—Enables you to use the same host name for the Onboard Administrator over time, although the dynamically assigned IP address might change. The host name is registered with a DNS server. DDNS updates the DNS server with new or changed records for IP addresses.<p class="listcontinue">Disabling Dynamic DNS on the Onboard Administrator stops the Onboard Administrator’s updates to the DNS server. However, note that some DHCP servers may have a provision to update DNS servers directly. To completely disable Dynamic DNS updates, disable Dynamic DNS both at the Onboard Administrator as well as at the DHCP server.</p></li>
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Use static IP settings for each Active (or Standby) <b>Onboard Administrator</b></b>—Manually set up static IP settings for the Onboard Administrator. The Standby check box is only shown if there is a Standby Onboard Administrator in the enclosure.<p class="tablespacerbefore" /><table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2"><tr><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Field
</th><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Possible value
</th><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Description
</th></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">DNS Host Name
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">1 to 32 characters including all alphanumeric characters, the dash (-), and the underscore (_).
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><p>The Onboard Administrator DNS host name. This setting applies to both IPv4 and IPv6 environments. The DNS host name can be assigned when using either DHCP or static IP settings.</p><p>Changing the Onboard Administrator DNS Name could cause a host name mismatch on the SSL certificate. You may have to update the certificate information on the affected Onboard Administrator, using the <a href="DCertificateAdministration.xml">Active Onboard Administrator Certificate Administration screen</a> or the <a href="DStandby_EM_short_name_CertificateAdministration.xml">Standby Onboard Administrator Certificate Administration screen</a>, as appropriate.</p></p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">IP Address
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Static IP address for the Onboard Administrator (required if static IP settings is selected).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Subnet Mask
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Subnet mask for the Onboard Administrator (required if static IP settings is selected).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Gateway
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Gateway address for the Onboard Administrator (required if static IP settings is selected).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">DNS Server 1
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">The IP address for the primary IPv4 DNS server.*
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">DNS Server 2
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">The IP address for the secondary IPv4 DNS server.*
</p></td></tr></table><p class="tablestatementtext">* The order in which the Onboard Administrator uses DNS servers is described in <a href="DIPSettingsunderenclosuresettings.xml">IPv4 Settings tab</a>.</p><p class="tablespacerafter" /></li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">To save new IPv4 settings, click <b>Next</b>.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>