<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DInterconnectBays" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Interconnect Bays</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DInterconnectBays.xml</source>
  <keywords>FQDN link support interconnect bay summary</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>Interconnect Bay Summary<p class="bodytext">In the Systems and Devices menu, the Interconnect Bays category lists all interconnects within the enclosure. Selecting the Interconnect Bays menu item opens the interconnect list with a grid showing the status of each interconnect within the enclosure.</p><p class="bodytext">The check box in the first column on the top row toggles all check boxes on or off for all enclosure interconnect devices, which is useful if you want to toggle the UID state for all interconnect devices at the same time. Otherwise, the first column contains check boxes that can be used to select individual interconnects. After you select the appropriate interconnects, you can use the Virtual Power or UID State dropdown menus (click the corresponding down arrow) to perform the appropriate action. For more information about these dropdown menus, scroll past the following table. </p><p class="tablespacerbefore" /><table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2"><tr><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Column
</th><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Description
</th></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Check box
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Click the check boxes next to the bay or bays where you want to apply the Virtual Power and UID State features.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Bay
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Bay in the enclosure of the corresponding interconnect device. This field displays only populated bays. Empty bays are not displayed in this table.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Status
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Overall status of the interconnect device. Possible values are Unknown, OK, Degraded, and Failed.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">UID
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Status of the UID on the interconnect device. Possible values are On (blue) or Off (gray).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Power State
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Power state of the interconnect device. Possible values are On or Off.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Module Type
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Network interface type for the interconnect device installed in this bay. Possible values are Ethernet or fiber.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Management URL
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><p>IPv4 address where the interconnect device can be managed and configured for use in the network. To view available Management URL address links (IPv4 and IPv6), click the down arrow to display a dropdown menu.</p><p>When FQDN link support is enabled and certain DNS configuration requirements are met, an FQDN-based address displays as the default Management URL. For more information about enabling FQDN link support, see the "<a href="DNetworkaccess.xml">Network Access</a>" page.</p></p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Product Name
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Common descriptive name for the interconnect device.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="tablespacerafter" /><p class="bodytext">Information on this page is current as of the last download. To view updated information, click <b>Refresh</b>.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Virtual Power</b></p><p class="bodytext">The Virtual Power dropdown menu enables the powering on or off of an interconnect device. It is recommended that only one device be powered on or off at a time using this feature.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>UID State</b></p><p class="bodytext">The UID State dropdown menu is used to set the UID light on the interconnect device. Turning on the UID light aids in locating a specific interconnect device within an enclosure. The UID lights can be turned on or off one at a time or in groups, depending on the check boxes.</p></content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>