<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DIPSettingsunderenclosuresettings" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Enclosure TCP/IP Settings</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DIPSettingsunderenclosuresettings.xml</source>
  <keywords>DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) dynamic DNS IP settings enclosure IPv4 Settings tab NIC settings Static Default TCP/IP settings Virtual Connect Manager</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>
            <b>IPv4 Settings tab</b>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>
            <b>Enclosure IP Mode</b>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">When enabled, the <b><b>Enclosure IP Mode</b></b> setting ensures all management applications point to the Active Onboard Administrator of the enclosure, using a single static IP address. This mode is for enclosures with an Active and Standby Onboard Administrator. When the Standby Onboard Administrator takes over the role of the Active Onboard Administrator, that Onboard Administrator assumes the IP address of the previous Active Onboard Administrator. This mode ensures the Enclosure IP Mode IP address is consistently pointing to the Active Onboard Administrator.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>
            <b>Enclosure IP Mode</b>
          </b> requires the Active Onboard Administrator to have a static IPv4 address or a static IPv6 address (IPv6 must be enabled). The Standby Onboard Administrator can be configured for DHCP or static IP settings. This mode is optional and is disabled by default.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To ensure that the Enclosure IP Mode setting is not changed when removing an Onboard Administrator module from the enclosure, do not remove the module while it is in the failover transition phase (about six minutes after a failover). After you remove a module, to ensure that all settings are transferred to the Standby module, add a replacement module and leave it in place for five minutes. If both the Active and Standby Onboard Administrator modules are powered off or removed from the enclosure at the same time, the Standby Onboard Administrator returns to the default network settings and all manually configured static network addresses are lost.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  This feature is disabled while in the FIPS Mode ON/DEBUG.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  Enabling <b><b style="color:#0066FF;">Enclosure IP Mode</b></b> on either the IPv4 Settings tab or the IPv6 Settings tab automatically enables this mode on both tabs.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>
            <b>Active and Standby </b>
            <b>Onboard Administrator<b> Network Settings</b></b>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">The Onboard Administrator allows the IPv4 network configuration to be based either on dynamically assigned IP addresses obtained from a DHCP server or on static IP addresses that you specify manually. You choose the basis for network configuration by selecting either the <b><b>DHCP</b></b> radio button or the <b><b>Static IP Settings</b></b> radio button. If you select <b><b>DHCP</b></b>, you can enable Dynamic DNS.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  Changing network settings on the Onboard Administrator that you are signed in to might disconnect you from that Onboard Administrator, in which case after you apply settings, you must sign in to the Onboard Administrator again.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>
              <b>DHCP</b>
            </b>—Obtains the IP address for the Onboard Administrator from a DHCP server.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>
              <b>Enable Dynamic DNS</b>
            </b>—With DHCP enabled, Dynamic DNS allows you to use the same host name for the Onboard Administrator over time, although the dynamically assigned IP address might change. The host name is registered with a DNS server. Dynamic DNS updates the DNS server with new or changed records for IP addresses. <p class="listcontinue">Disabling Dynamic DNS on the Onboard Administrator stops the Onboard Administrator’s updates to the DNS server. However, note that some DHCP servers may have a provision to update DNS servers directly. To completely disable Dynamic DNS updates, disable Dynamic DNS both at the Onboard Administrator as well as at the DHCP server.</p></li>
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>
              <b>Static IP Settings</b>
            </b>—Enables you to set up static IP settings for the Onboard Administrator manually.<p class="tablespacerbefore" /><table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2"><tr><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Field
</th><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Possible value
</th><th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Description
</th></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">DNS Host Name
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Can be 1 to 32 characters including all alphanumeric characters and the dash (-).
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><p>The DNS Name of the Onboard Administrator. This setting applies to both IPv4 and IPv6 environments. The DNS host name can be assigned when using either DHCP or static IP settings.</p><p>Changing the Onboard Administrator DNS Name could cause a host name mismatch on the SSL certificate. You may have to update the certificate information on the affected Onboard Administrator, using the <a href="DCertificateAdministration.xml">Active Onboard Administrator Certificate Administration screen</a> or the <a href="DStandby_EM_short_name_CertificateAdministration.xml">Standby Onboard Administrator Certificate Administration screen</a>, as appropriate.</p></p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">MAC Address
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">This is an informational field and cannot be changed.
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">The Onboard Administrator MAC address.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Domain Name
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">This is an informational field and cannot be changed.
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Displays the current domain name by each particular Onboard Administrator.
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">IP Address
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Static IP address for the Onboard Administrator (required if static IP settings is selected).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Subnet Mask
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Subnet mask for the Onboard Administrator (required if static IP settings is selected).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Gateway
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">Gateway address for the Onboard Administrator (required if static IP settings is selected).
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">IPv4 DNS 1
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">The IPv4 address for the first IPv4 DNS server.*
</p></td></tr><tr valign="top"><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">IPv4 DNS 2
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext">###.###.###.### where ### ranges from 0 to 255
</p></td><td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><p>The IPv4 address for the second IPv4 DNS server.*</p><p> </p></p></td></tr></table><p class="tablestatementtext">* The order in which the Onboard Administrator uses DNS servers is described after this table.</p><p class="tablespacerafter" /></li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">Depending on how many DNS servers are configured, the Onboard Administrator can use up to six DNS servers to look up an IP address: two IPv4 DNS servers (either static or DHCP assigned, but not both) and four IPv6 DNS servers (static or DHCP assigned, or both). The Onboard Administrator uses DNS servers in the following order:</p>
        <ol class="listnumber">
          <li class="listnumber">IPv4 DNS server 1 (static)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv6 DNS server 1 (static)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv4 DNS server 2 (static)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv6 DNS server 2 (static)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv4 DNS server 1 (DHCP assigned)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv6 DNS server 1 (DHCP assigned)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv4 DNS server 2 (DHCP assigned)</li>
          <li class="listnumber">IPv6 DNS server 2 (DHCP assigned)</li>
        </ol>
        <p class="bodytext">If any of the DNS servers in this list are not configured, the DNS servers that follow them in the list move up in order, accordingly. For example, if the DHCP-assigned IPv4 DNS servers 1 and 2 are not configured, the two DHCP-assigned IPv6 DNS servers move up to 5th and 6th in the list. As noted previously, IPv4 DNS servers can either be static or DHCP assigned, not both; so the maximum number of DNS servers that the Onboard Administrator can use is 6.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To save new IPv4 settings, click <b><b>Apply.</b></b></p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>