<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DLanguagePacktab" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Language Pack tab</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DLanguagePacktab.xml</source>
  <keywords>language pack</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">A list of installed language packs appears in this screen. The English language is embedded and cannot be removed. Only one additional language can be added using a language pack. Adding a new language pack automatically removes an existing language pack. To remove an existing language pack, select the check box and click <b>Remove</b>.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To add a language pack, you have two options:</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Upload</b>—To add a language pack from a local file, browse to the language pack file or enter the path of the language pack file in the textbox. The maximum number of characters in the file path is 256. Click <b>Upload</b>.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Download</b>—To add a language pack from a file located on a web server, enter an http:// path to the firmware image file. The maximum number of characters in the file path is 255. Supported protocols are HTTP, FTP, and TFTP. The URL is formatted as: protocol://host/path/filename. Enter the URL, and then click <b>Apply</b>.<b></b>After clicking Upload or Apply, a window displays the progress of the firmware download. When the download completes, a popup window displays the language pack as added.</li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">After installing a language pack, you can display the language on the Onboard Administrator GUI using your current browser's language preference option (preferred) or the Onboard Administrator User Preferences options:</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">To use your browser's settings for language preferences, add the language to the top of the browser's preferred languages list, and then use the Onboard Administrator <a href="DUserPreferences.xml">User Preferences</a> screen to select "Use browser settings." This method is preferred because the setting applies to any subsequent Onboard Administrator GUI sessions using this browser and to sessions with other Onboard Administrators, providing that the same language is installed on the other Onboard Administrator GUIs and their User Preferences setting is the default "Use browser settings."</li>
          <li class="listbullet">To use the Onboard Administrator <a href="DUserPreferences.xml">User Preferences</a> screen to display a specific language, select the language from the User Preferences list of available languages and click <b>Apply</b>. This setting overrides the browser's current language preference setting and persists with subsequent GUI sessions connecting to the same Onboard Administrator. However, the setting does not apply for GUI sessions with other Onboard Administrators. (The setting relies on a cookie that is valid only for the current Onboard Administrator IP address. If the IP address changes, the setting must be applied again from the new address.) To ensure that all pages of the Onboard Administrator's GUI inherit the selected language, click <b>Refresh </b>at the bottom of the User Preferences screen.</li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">Each of these settings is browser-specific. For example, a language setting for Internet Explorer does not affect the setting for Firefox. You do not have to use the same method on all browsers. After configuring your preferred language, to make the setting take effect, you may need to refresh or reload the web page.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  If the display language does not load properly, clear the browser cache and refresh the application by refreshing or reloading the browser.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">When logged in to a primary enclosure with linked enclosures, ensure that all linked enclosures have a compatible version of the language pack installed.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>