<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DNetworkaccess" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Network Access</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DNetworkaccess.xml</source>
  <keywords>DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) enable enclosure iLO Federation support enable SSH enable telnet enable web access enclosure iLO Federation support enabling enforce strong encryption IP address access restricting network access configuring protocol restrictions SSH enabling telnet enabling trusted IP addresses web access enabling</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>Protocols tab<p class="bodytext">You can select the following protocol settings to allow or restrict access to the Onboard Administrator.</p><ul class="listbullet"><li class="listbullet"><b>Enable Web Access (HTTP/HTTPS)</b>—This check box is selected by default. Clearing this check box disables HTTP/HTTPS access to the Onboard Administrator. Port 80 is used for HTTP, and port 443 is used for HTTPS.<p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/35928.png" alt="" /></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">CAUTION:</b>  Disabling Web Access (HTTP/HTTPS) disconnects all users attached to the Onboard Administrator through HTTP/HTTPS, including the administrator.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /></li><li class="listbullet"><b>Enable Secure Shell</b>—This check box is selected by default. Clearing this check box disables Secure Shell connections to the Onboard Administrator. SSH is disabled when Two-Factor Authentication is enabled. Disabling Two-Factor Authentication does not automatically re-enable SSH. To re-enable SSH, you must select the check box, and then click<b> Apply</b>. Port 22 is used for SSH.</li><li class="listbullet"><b>Enable Telnet</b>—This check box is not selected by default. Selecting this check box enables Telnet connections to the Onboard Administrator. Telnet is disabled when Two-Factor Authentication is enabled. Disabling Two-Factor Authentication does not automatically re-enable Telnet. To re-enable Telnet, you must select the check box, and then click <b>Apply</b>. Port 23 is used for Telnet.<p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  When the Onboard Administrator is operating in FIPS Mode ON/DEBUG, the Telnet protocol cannot be used.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /><p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  Telnet is disabled after a factory reset or when Two-Factor Authentication is enabled.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /></li><li class="listbullet"><b>Enable XML Reply</b>—This check box is selected by default. This check box enables XML data to be shared between the Onboard Administrator and other HP management tools such as HP Systems Insight Manager. To display the information that is shared by the Onboard Administrator if this protocol is enabled, click <b>View</b>.</li><li class="listbullet"><b>Enable Enclosure iLO Federation Support</b>—This check box is selected by default. This check box enables the Onboard Administrator support required to allow peer-to-peer network communication necessary for iLO Federation among suitably capable iLOs within the enclosure. When iLO Federation support is enabled for the enclosure, the active Onboard Administrator displays the device bay number of each bay for which the peer-to-peer network communication required for iLO Federation is enabled.<p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/35894.png" alt="" /></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">IMPORTANT:</b><b>Enable Enclosure iLO Federation Support</b> only enables Onboard Administrator support to allow the peer-to-peer network communication necessary for iLO Federation among iLOs within the enclosure. To fully enable iLO Federation, each iLO must have the appropriate firmware and be configured to participate in iLO Federation. For more information, see the<i> HP iLO 4 User Guide</i> at the <a href="http://www.hp.com/go/ilo/docs" target="ID0E2F">HP website</a>. 
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /></li><li class="listbullet"><b>Enable FQDN link support for accessing iLOs and interconnects</b>—This check box is not selected by default. Selecting this check box causes the Onboard Administrator to display an FQDN-based web address link in addition to the usual IP-based web address links for accessing an iLO or interconnect from the Onboard Administrator GUI. The Onboard Administrator queries a DNS server that performs a reverse lookup for the FQDN of the device and generates the FQDN-based web address (formatted as host-name.domain-name.com). An IPv4 DNS server must be configured on the Onboard Administrator, and the devices to be accessed must be registered for reverse lookup with the DNS name server. A DNS IP address must be configured on the Onboard Administrator (use the Enclosure TCP/IP <a href="DIPSettingsunderenclosuresettings.xml">IPv4 Settings tab</a>).<p class="listcontinue">When the FQDN setting is enabled, the lists of URL links for all the appropriate devices (iLOs and interconnects) are automatically refreshed and updated with the corresponding FQDNs. When the FQDN setting is disabled, the FQDN links of all the enclosure devices are removed from the Onboard Administrator and hence are not displayed.</p><p class="listcontinue">FQDN link support is useful in IPv6-based remote access environments that depend on an IPv4-based enclosure management network with IPv4 DNS. It is not meant for pure IPv6 environments with IPv6 DNS.</p></li></ul><p class="bodytext">To save the settings, click <b>Apply.</b></p></content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>