<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DPowerMeter" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Power Meter</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DPowerMeter.xml</source>
  <keywords>power meter power meter graphical view</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>Graphical View tab<p class="bodytext">This screen enables you to see a graphical view of the power readings for the enclosure.</p><p class="bodytext">To toggle between Watts, Btu/hr, and Amps, click <b>Show Values.</b></p><p class="bodytext">The <b>Line Voltage</b> value is used to provide conversion to Amps. The default value is based on the power supply hardware model, not the actual line voltage. Select the actual line voltage for the enclosure for a more accurate Amps conversion.</p><p class="bodytext">To view updated power meter information, click <b>Refresh Page.</b></p><p class="bodytext"><b>Average Power data graph</b></p><p class="bodytext">This graph displays the power usage of the enclosure over the previous 24 hours. The Onboard Administrator collects power usage and Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap information from the enclosure every 5 minutes. For each 5 minute time period, the peak and average power usage and the cap for that time period are stored in a circular buffer. These values appear in the form of a bar graph, with the average value in blue, the peak value in red, and the cap value in black. This data is reset when the enclosure is reset. You can choose what appears on the bar graph by selecting or clearing the<b> Average, Cap, Derated, Rated,</b> and <b>Min</b> check boxes.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Present Power</b></p><p class="bodytext">This value represents the number of watts being consumed by all devices in the enclosure.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Most Recent Power Meter Reading</b></p><p class="bodytext">This value represents the most recent power reading from the enclosure.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Peak Power data graph</b></p><p class="bodytext">This graph displays the peak power usage and the Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap over the previous 24 hours.</p><p class="bodytext">The label Peak Power becomes Peak Power (Side A + Side B) when N+N redundant power is in place, indicating that the peak is divided across two circuits. Also, two graphs appear: one for Side A and one for Side B.</p><p class="bodytext">The power distribution between Side A and Side B is estimated from the number of active power supplies on each side. If redundancy is lost, the lost side displays peak power of zero.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap</b></p><p class="bodytext">This value represents the most recent Enclosure Dynamic Power Cap reading from the enclosure.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Average Power Reading</b></p><p class="bodytext">This value represents the average of the power readings from the enclosure over the last 24-hour period. If the enclosure has not been running for 24 hours, then the value is the average of all the readings since the enclosure was powered up.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Peak Power Reading</b></p><p class="bodytext">This value represents the peak power readings from the enclosure over the last 24-hour period. If the enclosure has not been running for 24 hours, then the value is the maximum of all the readings since the enclosure was powered up or the Onboard Administrator was reset.</p><p class="bodytext">The label Peak Power Reading becomes Peak Power Reading (Side A + Side B) when N+N redundant power is in place, indicating that the peak is divided across two circuits.</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Minimum Power Reading</b></p><p class="bodytext">This value represents the minimum power readings from the enclosure over the last 24-hour period. If the enclosure has not been running for 24 hours, then the value is the minimum of all the readings since the enclosure was powered up.</p></content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>