<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DRemote_Support_Configuration_DC" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Insight Remote Support Registration</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DRemote_Support_Configuration_DC.xml</source>
  <keywords>Insight Remote Support registration Remote Support prerequisites Remote Support registration</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">HP has developed a service and support experience that automates many day-to-day tasks and helps you reduce risk. HP integrates an online, personalized dashboard (HP Insight Online), a support portal and mobile application (HP Support Center Mobile), and 24x7 remote support (HP Insight Remote Support) for the consolidated infrastructure.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">When you use the embedded Remote Support functionality with an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure, you can choose from the following configuration options:</p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Insight Online direct connect</b>—Register an enclosure to communicate directly to HP Insight Online without the need to set up an HP Insight Remote Support centralized Hosting Device in your local environment. HP Insight Online will be your primary interface for remote support information. The direct connect configuration is available in Onboard Administrator 4.11 and later.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">
            <b>Insight Remote Support central connect</b>—Register an enclosure to communicate to HP through an HP Insight Remote Support centralized Hosting Device in your local environment. All configuration and service event information is routed through the Hosting Device. This information can be viewed by using the local HP Insight RS Console or the web-based view in HP Insight Online. The central connect configuration is available on Onboard Administrator 3.60 and later.</li>
        </ul>Data Collected by Insight Remote Support<p class="bodytext">When the BladeSystem Enclosure is registered with Insight Remote Support, the following information about the BladeSystem Enclosure shared infrastructure components within the enclosure is sent to HP:</p><ul class="listbullet"><li class="listbullet">Registration—As part of the enclosure registration process, for central connect, the Onboard Administrator sends to the Insight Remote Support hosting server the data that uniquely identifies the enclosure hardware. For direct connect, the Onboard Administrator sends that data directly to a web service in the Remote Support Data Center.<p class="listcontinue">Examples of data that is collected include:</p><ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure name</li><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure product name</li><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure part number </li><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure serial number</li><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure manufacturer name</li><li class="listbullet2">Onboard Administrator firmware version</li><li class="listbullet2">Onboard Administrator IP and MAC addresses</li></ul></li><li class="listbullet">Service events—As part of the service event process, Onboard Administrator sends data to uniquely identify the relevant hardware component to the Insight Remote Support hosting device.<p class="listcontinue">Examples of data that is collected include:</p><ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure model</li><li class="listbullet2">Enclosure serial number</li><li class="listbullet2">Part number of the relevant hardware component</li><li class="listbullet2">Description, location, and other identifying characteristics of the relevant hardware component</li></ul><p class="listcontinue">For more information, see "<a href="DRemote_Support_Service_Events.xml">Insight Remote Support Service Events</a>."</p></li><li class="listbullet">Data collections—As part of the data collection process, the Onboard Administrator sends data to Insight Remote Support to enable proactive advice and consulting. Information is sent for the enclosure hardware as well as populated system components including the LCD module, Onboard Administrator modules, enclosure fan modules, enclosure power supply modules, interconnect modules and server blades.<p class="listcontinue">Examples of data that is collected for these system components include:</p><ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">Hardware module descriptors such as manufacturer, product name, serial number, UUID, part number, and location within the enclosure</li><li class="listbullet2">Firmware revision</li><li class="listbullet2">Diagnostic and status information</li><li class="listbullet2">Power and thermal configuration and status information</li><li class="listbullet2">Network and port mapping information</li></ul><p class="listcontinue">For more information, see "<a href="DRemote_Support_Data_Collections.xml">Insight Remote Support Data Collections</a>."</p></li></ul>Prerequisites<p class="bodytext">Before registering, verify that the following prerequisites are met:</p><ul class="listbullet"><li class="listbullet">A supported version of the OA firmware is installed on all OA modules in the enclosure.<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">Version 3.60 or later is required for Insight Remote Support central connect registration.</li><li class="listbullet2">Version 4.11 or later is required for Insight Online direct connect registration.</li></ul><p class="listcontinue">You can download the latest firmware from the <a href="http://www.hp.com/go/oa" target="ID0E2D">HP website</a>.</p></li><li class="listbullet">For Insight Online direct connect only: A DNS server is configured in the Onboard Administrator. This is required for communication between iLO and Insight Online.</li><li class="listbullet">For Insight Remote Support central connect only: Insight RS version 7.0.5 or later is installed and configured on the Insight RS hosting device.<p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  A valid certificate is required if connecting to an HP Insight Remote Support Hosting Device and the Onboard Administrator is operating in FIPS Mode. 
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /><p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  When the Onboard Administrator is operating in FIPS Mode, certificates must have a minimum RSA key length of 2048 bits, and the signature hash algorithm must be SHA1, SHA-224, SHA-256, SHA-384, or SHA-512. 
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /></li></ul>Registering for Insight Remote Support using the OA web interface<p class="bodytext">HP Insight Remote Support provides automatic submission of hardware events to HP to prevent downtime and enable faster issue resolution. You can register directly to HP or through an Insight RS Hosting Device.</p>Registering for Insight Remote Support by using direct connect<p class="procedurelead-in">To register an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure for Insight Online direct connect, use the following procedure. When you register for Insight Online direct connect, you must complete steps in both the OA interface and the Insight Online portal.</p><ol class="listnumber"><li class="listnumber">Verify that the system meets the prerequisites for using the Insight Remote Support solution. For more information, see the "Prerequisites" section.</li><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;Remote Support</b> page.</li><li class="listnumber">Under the <b>Registration </b>tab, select <b>Register this enclosure directly to HP</b>.<b></b>The page updates to show the direct connect registration options.</li><li class="listnumber">Enter your HP Passport credentials in the <b>HP Passport User ID</b> and <b>HP Passport Password </b>boxes.<p class="alertspacerbefore" /><table width="90%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0"><tr valign="top"><td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/35894.png" alt="" /></p></td><td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left"><p class="tablebodytext"><b style="color:#0066FF;">IMPORTANT:</b>  Enter your HP Passport User ID in the <b>HP Passport User ID</b> box. In most cases, your HP Passport User ID is the email address you used during the HP Passport registration process. If you changed your User ID in HPSC, ensure that you enter your User ID and not your email address.
</p></td></tr></table><p class="alertspacerafter" /></li><li class="listnumber">Optional: If your HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure uses a web proxy server to access the Internet, enter the following information:<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Server</b></li><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Username</b></li><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Password</b></li><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Port</b></li></ul></li><li class="listnumber">Select the <b>I accept the terms and conditions of the HP Software License Agreement and the HP Insight Management Additional License Authorization</b> check box. These documents can be viewed at the <a href="http://www.hp.com/go/SWLicensing" target="ID0E5AAC">HP Software License Documents website</a>. </li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>Register</b>.<b></b>Clicking <b>Register</b> is Step 1 of a two-step registration process. Step 2 is completed in HP Insight Online.<p class="listcontinue">By registering, you agree to send registration, service events, and configuration data to HP. All data collected and sent to HP will be managed according to the HP Data Privacy Policy. You can view the HP Data Privacy Policy at the <a href="http://www.hp.com/go/privacy" target="ID0EQBAC">HP website</a>.</p><p class="listcontinue">When Step 1 of the registration process begins, the following message appears: </p><p class="listcontinue"><tt>Step 1 of registration in progress, please wait...</tt></p><p class="listcontinue">When Step 1 is finished, the following message appears: </p><p class="listcontinue"><tt>Step 1 of remote support registration has been completed. Please proceed to step 2 to complete the registration process.</tt></p><p class="listcontinue">Allow up to 5 minutes for your registration request to be fully processed.</p></li><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <a href="http://www.hp.com/go/insightonline." target="ID0EKCAC">HP Insight Online website</a>, and then log in with your HP Passport account credentials.</li><li class="listnumber">Follow the onscreen instructions in Insight Online, and provide your site, contact, and partner information so HP can deliver service for your enclosure. For detailed instructions, see the <i>HP Insight Remote Support and Insight Online Setup Guide for HP ProLiant Servers and HP BladeSystem c-Class Enclosures.</i></li><li class="listnumber">Return to the <b>Remote Support</b> page in the OA web interface, and select the <b>Please confirm that you have completed the registration process in HP Insight Online</b> check box, and then click <b>Apply.</b><p class="listcontinue">The following message appears: 
      <tt>Are you sure you have completed registration in HP Insight Online?</tt><tt>Click OK to confirm or Cancel to cancel.</tt></p></li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>OK</b>. A message similar to the following appears:<p class="listcontinue"><tt>Successfully registered!</tt></p><p class="listcontinue"><tt>HP Passport User ID used to register this enclosure: &lt;HP passport User ID&gt;.</tt></p></li><li class="listnumber">Optional: Send a test event to confirm the connection between OA and Insight Remote Support:<ol class="listnumber2"><li class="listnumber2">Go to <b>Enclosure Settings &gt; Remote Support.</b></li><li class="listnumber2">Click the <b><a href="DRemote_Support_Service_Events.xml">Service Events</a></b><b></b>tab.</li><li class="listnumber2">Click <b>Send Test Event</b>.</li></ol></li><li class="listnumber">Optional: If you want to receive email alerts about system events, configure AlertMail on the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;<a href="DAlertmailsettings.xml">AlertMail</a></b>page.</li></ol>Editing the web proxy settings<p class="bodytext">Proxy settings must be maintained to enable your enclosure to continue to send Remote Support data to HP. If the proxy settings change, use the following procedure to edit them:</p><ol class="listnumber"><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;Remote Support </b>page.</li><li class="listnumber">Update the following settings, as needed:<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Server—</b>Enter the web proxy server in the format http://&lt;hostname or IP address&gt;.</li><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Port</b></li><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Username</b></li><li class="listbullet2"><b>Web Proxy Password</b></li></ul></li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>Apply.</b></li></ol>Registering for Insight Remote Support by using central connect<p class="procedurelead-in">To register an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure for Insight Remote Support central connect, use the following procedure: </p><ol class="listnumber"><li class="listnumber">Verify that the system meets the prerequisites for using Insight Remote Support. For more information, see the "Prerequisites" section.</li><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;<a href="DNetworkaccess.xml">Network Access</a></b> page and click the <b>Protocol </b>tab.</li><li class="listnumber">Verify that the Enable XML Reply check box is selected.<p class="listcontinue">If this check box is not selected, the Insight RS hosting device cannot collect data from the Onboard Administrator.</p></li><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;Remote Support</b> page.</li><li class="listnumber">Select <b>Register this enclosure through an HP Insight Remote Support centralized hosting device. </b>The page updates to show the central connect registration options.</li><li class="listnumber">Enter the Insight RS hosting device host name or IP address and port number. The default port is 7906.</li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>Register. </b>By registering, you agree to send registration, service events, and configuration data to HP. All data collected and sent to HP will be managed according to the HP Data Privacy Policy. You can view the HP Data Privacy Policy at the <a href="http://www.hp.com/go/privacy" target="ID0EYGAC">HP website</a>. The following message appears:<p class="listcontinue"><tt>Device successfully registered.</tt></p></li><li class="listnumber">Optional: Send a test event to confirm the connection between OA and Insight Remote Support:<ol class="listnumber2"><li class="listnumber2">Go to <b>Enclosure Settings &gt; Remote Support.</b></li><li class="listnumber2">Click the <b><a href="DRemote_Support_Service_Events.xml">Service Events</a></b><b></b>tab.</li><li class="listnumber2">Click <b>Send Test Event</b>.</li></ol></li></ol>Unregistering an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure from Insight Online direct connect<ol class="listnumber"><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;Remote Support</b> page.</li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>Unregister.</b><p class="listcontinue">The following message appears: <tt>Are you sure you want to un-register and disable HP Insight Remote Support?</tt></p></li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>OK.</b><p class="listcontinue">The following message appears: <tt>Un-registration in progress. Please wait…</tt></p><p class="listcontinue">When the un-registration is finished, the Remote Support page displays the following message: </p><p class="listcontinue"><tt>The enclosure is not registered.</tt></p></li></ol>Unregistering an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure from Insight Remote Support central connect<ol class="listnumber"><li class="listnumber">Log in to the Insight RS Console.</li><li class="listnumber">Do one of the following:<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">To stop monitoring an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure temporarily, select the enclosure on the <b>Devices&gt;Device Summary </b>tab in the HP Insight RS Console, and then select <b>ACTIONS&gt;DISABLE SELECTED</b>.</li><li class="listbullet2">To stop monitoring an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure permanently, delete the enclosure from the Insight RS Console. To delete the enclosure, select it on the <b>Device Summary </b>tab, and then select <b>ACTIONS&gt;DELETE SELECTED</b>.</li></ul><p class="listcontinue">Disabling or deleting the enclosure in the Insight RS Console does not unregister the enclosure in OA. For OA to be aware that an enclosure is disabled, you must use OA to unregister from Insight Remote Support.</p></li><li class="listnumber">Navigate to the <b>Enclosure Information&gt;Enclosure Settings&gt;Remote Support</b> page in the OA web interface.</li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>Unregister.</b><p class="listcontinue">The following message appears: <tt>Are you sure you want to un-register and disable HP Insight Remote Support?</tt></p></li><li class="listnumber">Click <b>OK.</b><p class="listcontinue">The following message appears: <tt>The enclosure is not registered.</tt></p></li></ol>Connection error during OA direct connect registration<p class="bodytext"><b>Issue</b>: The following error occurs when you try to register an HP BladeSystem c-Class enclosure for Insight Online direct connect:</p><p class="bodytext"><tt>Failed to resolve HP Insight Remote Support direct connect web service. Please verify DNS settings, proxy settings and connectivity.</tt></p><p class="bodytext"><b>Solution 1</b>: Verify that the DNS settings are configured correctly in OA. You can use the OA web interface or CLI to perform this task:</p><ul class="listbullet"><li class="listbullet">Log in to the OA web interface and navigate to the <b><a href="DIPSettingsforActiveOA.xml">Active Onboard Administrator TCP/IP Settings</a></b> page. Verify that the DNS configuration is correct. To edit the configuration, click the following link at the bottom of the screen: <b>Click here to modify the TCP/IP settings.</b></li><li class="listbullet">Log in to the OA CLI interface and run the <tt>SHOW NETWORK</tt> command. Verify that the DNS configuration is correct. To edit the configuration, use the <tt>ADD OA DNS</tt> command.</li></ul><p class="bodytext"><b>Solution 2</b>: Verify that the web proxy settings are configured correctly in OA. For information about editing the web proxy settings, see “Editing the web proxy settings.”</p><p class="bodytext"><b>Solution 3</b>: Verify that your configuration meets the network requirements for Insight Online direct connect.</p><p class="bodytext" /></content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>