<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DResetFactoryDefaults" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Reset factory defaults</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DResetFactoryDefaults.xml</source>
  <keywords>factory defaults resetting</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/35894.png" alt="" />
              </p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">IMPORTANT:</b>  If the enclosure is in VC mode, you must clear the mode before resetting factory defaults. 
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/35894.png" alt="" />
              </p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">IMPORTANT:</b>  Before resetting factory defaults, save your configuration. Click <b>SHOW CONFIG</b> to download a script containing your current configuration. You can use this script later to restore settings that are lost after a factory reset.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  After a factory reset, the enclosure IPv6 network settings (IPv6, SLAAC, and DHCPv6) are enabled by default. 
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">When you reset the enclosure to the factory defaults all enclosure settings are reset except the built-in Administrator password. All Alert Mail, Network and Network Protocol, SNMP, and Power Management settings are reset.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To reset the enclosure, click <b>Reset Factory Defaults</b>. A confirmation screen appears. To confirm resetting the enclosure, click <b>OK</b>, or to exit without resetting the enclosure to factory defaults, click <b>Cancel</b>.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  This feature is disabled while in the FIPS Mode ON/DEBUG.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="procedurelead-in">To view a current configuration for the enclosure:</p>
        <ol class="listnumber">
          <li class="listnumber">Click the <b>SHOW CONFIG</b> link. The configuration opens in a new browser window.</li>
          <li class="listnumber">To save the configuration as a text file, choose one of the following options:<ul class="listbullet2"><li class="listbullet2">If you use Microsoft Internet Explorer, select <b>Save As</b>.</li><li class="listbullet2">If you use Mozilla Firefox, select <b>Save Page As</b>.</li><li class="listbullet2">If you use Google Chrome, select <b>Save Link As</b>.</li></ul></li>
        </ol>
        <p class="bodytext">For security, the retrieved current configuration does not contain any user passwords. You can edit the script manually to add the user passwords after the user name on the ADD USER lines. Also, the retrieved current configuration does not contain any of the LCD settings (Lock Buttons, Enable PIN Protection, and PIN Code). These settings cannot be added using the configuration script.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">Clearing the VC mode removes all VC settings from the enclosure. Power off all VC-configured servers before clearing the VC mode. If servers are not powered down, they might maintain the VC settings until they are rebooted. You must clear the VC mode before changing to the FIPS Mode OFF/ON/DEBUG.</p>
        <p class="procedurelead-in">To clear the VC Mode:</p>
        <ol class="listnumber">
          <li class="listnumber">Click <b>Clear VC Mode</b>. A confirmation screen appears, stating <tt>All servers should be powered off and not configured by Virtual Connect prior to clearing VC mode. Are you sure that you wish to clear VC mode?</tt></li>
          <li class="listnumber">Click <b>OK</b>.</li>
        </ol>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>