<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DServerBayPortMapping" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Device Bay Port Mapping for c7000 Enclosure</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DServerBayPortMapping.xml</source>
  <keywords>port mapping</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="figure">
          <b>Half-height server blade</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext" />
        <p class="figure">
          <img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/66936.png" alt="Half-height server blade" />
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">In this diagram, N equals the number of the server blade in the enclosure and the port number on the switch. For example, if a server blade is inserted into slot 1, it is considered device 1, and the ports that will be used in switch 1 and switch 2 are ports 1 and 1, respectively. If a server blade is inserted into slot 2, then the ports used on switch 1 and switch 2 are ports 2 and 2. This convention changes for the full-height server blades as seen in the next diagram.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Full-height server blade</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext" />
        <p class="figure">
          <img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/66934.png" alt="Full-height server blade" />
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">In this diagram, N equals the number of the blade in the enclosure and the port number for the switch. For example, if a blade is inserted into slot 1, it is considered device 1. Because full-height server blades take up the space of two half-height server blades, the enclosure is limited to a maximum of eight full-height server blades. Port mapping from these full-height server blades might initially appear to be different than the half-height server blades, but they use very similar conventions.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">Just as in a half-height server blade, if a blade is inserted into slot 1, it is considered device 1, but it has a second set of ports that will also map to switches 1 and 2. With the full-height server blade, an N/N+8 scheme is used on the switches. Therefore, server blade 1 will map to ports 1 and 9 on both switches, as N=1. For a server blade inserted into slot 2, the four ports used on switches 1 and 2 would then be 2 and 10, as N=2.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Double dense server blade</b>
        </p>
        <p class="figure">
          <img src="/120814-042457/Help/images/106896.png" alt="" />
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Related topics</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <a href="DServerBayPortMappingGraphicalView.xml">Device Bay Port Mapping Graphical View for c7000 Enclosure</a>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <a href="DServerBayPortMappingTableView.xml">Device Bay Port Mapping Table View</a>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <a href="DInterconnectBayPortMapping.xml">Interconnect Bay Port Mapping</a>
        </p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>