<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DSignedInUsers" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Signed In Users</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DSignedInUsers.xml</source>
  <keywords>signed in users users signed in</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">This screen displays all the current sessions signed in to the Onboard Administrator. This screen is only available to Administrators with Onboard Administrator access. The Administrator can terminate sessions, disable users, and delete users from this screen.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Current Session</b>—This table lists the session created when you signed in to the Onboard Administrator.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Other Sessions</b>—This table lists the other users signed in to the Onboard Administrator.</p>
        <p class="tablespacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
          <tr>
            <th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Column
</th>
            <th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Description
</th>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Check box
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Used to select a user or all users.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Username
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The name of the user signed in to the enclosure.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">IP Address
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <p>The user account IP address. The IP address of the session can be an enclosure linked address if it looks like "169.254.1.x". These sessions are created by other linked enclosures. Performing a delete, disable, or terminate session on a user with a linked enclosure IP address might end the enclosure link sessions of other users.</p>
                <p>For KVM and Serial logins the IP address field displays Local.</p>
              </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Age
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The length of time, measured in days, hours, minutes and seconds, the user account has been signed in.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Idle Time
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The length of time, measured in days, hours, minutes and seconds, the signed in account has been idle.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">User Type
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The type of user signed in to the enclosure. Possible values are Local, LDAP, or HP SSO.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Session Type
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The type of session of the signed in user. Possible values are Web, SSH, Telnet, KVM, Serial, and Factory Diagnostics.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">OA Module
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The Onboard Administrator module the user is signed into. Possible values are Active or Standby.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Delete Users</b>—Select a user or users to be deleted by selecting the check box next to the name of the user, and click <b>Delete Users</b>. You cannot delete your own account or the built-in Administrator account.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Disable Users</b>—Select a user or users to be disabled by selecting the check box next to the name of the user, and click <b>Disable Users</b>. You cannot disable your own account or the built-in Administrator account.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Terminate Sessions</b>—Select a user or users whose sessions you want to terminate by selecting the check box next to the name of the user, and click <b>Terminate Sessions</b>. You cannot terminate your own session.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>