<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DSNMPSettings" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>SNMP Settings</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DSNMPSettings.xml</source>
  <keywords>community string SNMP settings SNMP test testing SNMP</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">SNMP is a protocol used to communicate management information between network management applications and HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator. The Onboard Administrator supports SNMP Version 1, Version 2, and Version 3, and several groups from the standard MIB-II MIB. Additional information about the enclosure infrastructure is available in the HP Rack Information MIB. The Rack Information MIB (CPQRACK-MIB) is part of the Insight Management MIBs and is found on the Management CD in the ProLiant Essentials Foundation Pack.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">SNMPv3 provides support for encryption of the agent data via either DES or AES128, using a user-provided password. A dedicated set of SNMP users is maintained each with a set of authorization and authentication passwords, along with another set of per user permissions.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">The SNMP Settings screen enables you to enter system information and community strings and designate the management stations that can receive SNMP traps from the Onboard Administrator. If you select <b>Enable SNMP</b>, then the Onboard Administrator responds to SNMP requests over UDP port 162. Port 162 is the standard UDP port used to send and retrieve SNMP messages.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">In the System Information subcategory, information about the Onboard Administrator SNMP system can be enabled and configured.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">The Enable SNMP check box is not selected by default. When this check box is selected, the Onboard Administrator can be polled for status and basic information. A SNMP client can clear SNMP alerts and status only when you enable the Write Community string. To disable SNMP access to the Onboard Administrator, clear the <b>Enable SNMP</b> check box.</p>
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  While in FIPS Mode ON/DEBUG, the SNMPv1 and SNMPv2 are disabled, and you can create only SNMPv3 traps.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="tablespacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
          <tr>
            <th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Field
</th>
            <th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Possible value
</th>
            <th class="tableheading" style="border:1px solid #010101;text-align:left;">Description
</th>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">System Location
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">0 to 20 characters including all printable characters and the space
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The SNMP location of the enclosure typically used to identify the physical or topographical location of the Onboard Administrator.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">System Contact
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">0 to 20 characters including all printable characters and the space
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The name of the system contact, used to identify an individual or group of individuals who are to be contacted in the event of any status change in the HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Read Community
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">0 to 20 characters including all printable characters and the space
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The Read Community string enables the client to read information but not to manipulate the alerts or status of the HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator through SNMPv1 or SNMPv2. The default community name is "public" and will allow a user to receive notification traps and alerts, but not to change or manipulate the status.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Write Community
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">0 to 20 characters including all printable characters and the space
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">The Write Community string enables the client to manipulate alerts of HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator status through SNMPv1 or SNMPv2. You can remotely clear alerts and mark them as "viewed" or otherwise through their SNMP management client through the SNMP agents.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">Engine ID String
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">1 to 27 printable characters, final Engine ID will be a hexadecimal string that begins with '0x' and is derived from this string
</p>
            </td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <p>The Engine ID String is used to create the engine ID hex value.</p>
                <p>The engine ID is combined with the user name to create a SNMPv3 user for each enclosure. When the engine ID is unique to an enclosure, users with the same name on different enclosures are unique. </p>
                <p>The Engine ID string defaults to the serial number of the enclosure.</p>
              </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="tablespacerafter" />
        <p class="bodytext">After editing any field in this subcategory, to save the changes, click <b>Apply</b>.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Adding SNMP alert destinations</b>
        </p>
        <p class="bodytext">To remove a current SNMP alert destination, select the check box, and click <b>Delete</b>.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To add a new SNMP alert destination, click <b>New</b>. The <a href="DAddSNMPAlert.xml">Add SNMP Alert</a> screen appears.</p>
        <p class="bodytext">To send a test SNMP trap to all of the configured trap destinations, click <b>Send Test Alert</b>. You must enable SNMP to use this function.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>