<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DUserPreferences" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>User Preferences</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DUserPreferences.xml</source>
  <keywords>display language user preferences</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">To change the display language, select a display language from the dropdown list, and then click <b>Apply.</b> The selected language overrides the browser's current language preference setting and persists with subsequent GUI sessions with the same Onboard Administrator. However, the setting does not apply for GUI sessions with other Onboard Administrators. (The setting relies on a cookie that is valid only for the current Onboard Administrator IP address. If the IP address changes, the setting must be applied again from the new address.)</p>
        <p class="procedurelead-in">If you want the language to display for connections to other Onboard Administrator GUIs using this browser:</p>
        <ol class="listnumber">
          <li class="listnumber">Add the language to the top of the browser's preferred language list.</li>
          <li class="listnumber">On the Onboard Administrator User Preferences screen, select "Use browser settings" from the dropdown list.</li>
          <li class="listnumber">Refresh the display language by clicking <b>Apply</b>. The corresponding language pack must be installed on the other Onboard Administrators; for more information about installing a language pack, see the <a href="DLanguagePacktab.xml">Active Onboard Administrator Language Pack tab</a>.<p class="listcontinue">If "Use browser settings" is already set, refresh the display language without changing the setting by clicking <b>Refresh</b>.</p></li>
        </ol>
        <p class="bodytext">The User Preferences dropdown list includes only those languages that have been installed or are embedded on the Onboard Administrator. If you set the browser language preference to a language that is not listed, the Onboard Administrator GUI will not use the browser language setting; the GUI uses the default language (English) instead.</p>
        <p class="bodytext" />
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  If the display language does not load properly, clear the browser cache and refresh the application by refreshing or reloading the browser.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
        <p class="alertspacerbefore" />
        <table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <tr valign="top">
            <td style="border:0px;width:1%;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext"></p>
            </td>
            <td style="border-top:1px solid #0066FF;border-right:0px;border-bottom:1px solid #0066FF;border-left:0px;" align="left">
              <p class="tablebodytext">
                <b style="color:#0066FF;">NOTE:</b>  If you are using an installed language pack with the Onboard Administrator GUI, and your browser does not display all characters correctly, make sure the operating system has the corresponding language support installed.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p class="alertspacerafter" />
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>