<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DWizardsOptionsandHelpMenus" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/02/xpath-functions">
  <title>Wizards, options, and help menus</title>
  <source>/120814-042457/Help/en/topics/DWizardsOptionsandHelpMenus.xml</source>
  <keywords>Firmware Update Wizard help contents session time-out settings using Help</keywords>
  <intro />
  <sections>
    <section>
      <desc />
      <content>
        <p class="bodytext">Menu selections at the top of the GUI screen include:</p>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Wizards</b>
        </p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">First Time Setup—Select this option to launch the First Time Setup Wizard.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">Startup Settings&gt;Launch Startup Wizard at startup—Select this option to enable the launching of the First Time Startup Wizard the next time you sign in to the Onboard Administrator.</li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Options</b>
        </p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">Refresh Enclosure Information—Select this option to refresh all information on the screen.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">Refresh Rack Topology—Select this option to enable full topology (Linked Mode).</li>
          <li class="listbullet">User Preferences—Select this option to set up your application display language from the drop down list.</li>
        </ul>
        <p class="bodytext">
          <b>Help</b>
        </p>
        <ul class="listbullet">
          <li class="listbullet">Table of Contents—Select this option to display the table of contents of the HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator GUI Online Help.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">Index—Select this option to display the index of the HP BladeSystem Onboard Administrator GUI Online Help.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">For This Page—Select this option to display help information for the present GUI screen. The same information will be displayed if you click the Help icon "?" on the top right of this screen.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">HP BladeSystem on hp.com—Select this option to access the HP BladeSystem home page.</li>
          <li class="listbullet">About HP Onboard Administrator—Select this option to display information on the hardware and firmware versions of the Onboard Administrators.</li>
        </ul>
      </content>
    </section>
  </sections>
</topic>