<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/120814-042457/Help/stylesheets/help-topic.xsl"?>
<topic topic-id="DEventSupport" parent-id="" author="slamasla" modified="10-8-2009" type="reference">
<source>/120814-042457/help/en/topics/gsoap-eventing.xml</source>
<title>Event Support</title>  
<keywords>events eventing</keywords>
<intro></intro>
<sections>
  <section>
    <desc/>
    <content>
      The gSoap Library Analyzer 2&#x2122; utility provides a basic eventing process to assist in testing. 
      <p>
        <attention type="information">
          <p>
            If you already have an open GUI session from the same IP address running within the same browser instance,
            the gSoap Library Analyzer 2&#x2122; will use the same session cookies for authentication as
            the original instance. 
          </p>   
          <p>
            However, registering for events from the gSoap Library Analyzer 2&#x2122; will not cause 
            conflicts because a new event queue with a unique PID is created for each client that 
            successfully subscribes for events.
          </p>
        </attention>
      </p>
      <p>
        If a session key is automatically set when you load the gSoap Library Analyzer 2&#x2122; page, then there is
        already a session cookie resident in the browser instance. In order to preserve the original session cookie
        when the gSoap Library Analyzer 2&#x2122; signs out, the user will be prompted for a decision about whether 
        to delete the cookie or leave it intact.
      </p>
      <p>
        <h5>Description</h5>
        After a successful sign in, you may turn on events by clicking the start events button. This will invoke a 
        'subscribeForEvents' soap call, and if it succeeds the eventing icon will turn green and a continuous polling
        loop will begin to gather events.
      </p>
      <p>
        Each time an event is retrieved, the green eventing icon will turn blue briefly to indicate an event has arrived. The
        event manager will store a maximum of 100 events, after which it will drop the oldest event from its collection as each
        new event arrives.
      </p>
      <p>
        <h5>Eventing Options</h5>
        <table cellpadding="5" border="0" cellspacing="0" margin="0" style="width:100%;border-collapse:collapse;vertical-align:top;">
          <tr>
            <th style="text-align:left;border:1px solid #010101;white-space:nowrap">Option or Button</th>
            <th style="text-align:left;border:1px solid #010101;white-space:nowrap;">Description</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">Capture Heartbeats</td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">Check this checkbox to add heartbeat events to the collection. Uncheck
              this checkbox to ignore heartbeat events.
              <br />
              <br />
              <b>Note:</b> Heartbeats can be helpful for verifying that the eventing service is running, especially when
              there is no other activtiy that would cause an event to be generated.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">show events</td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">Click this button to display the collection of events in the results
            window in descending order (last received events appear first).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">reset events</td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">Click this button to clear the event collection. This does not stop
            eventing.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">stop events</td>
            <td style="border:1px solid #010101;">Click this button to completely stop the event polling process and unsubscribe. 
            You do not have to do this before signing out because it will happen automatically during the sign out process.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </p>
      <br />
      <br />
    </content>
  </section>
</sections>
</topic>
